This man... was the driver of the
carriage that Lady Anastasia rode in.
Was it you?
Did you kill Anastasia Shaderan?
Episode 9 "In Pursuit
of Anastasia's Spirit"
As I thought, it doesn't seem
likely he'll simply tell us.
I've brought him.
Johan...
I've heard you're from the Bandelee
Islands. I'm from the same area.
What island were you born on?
Y-You're Bandeleese?
Why are you working in a castle?
Count Granado's mother is a
refugee from another country.
He has also grown up suffering insults
from the people of this kingdom.
He doesn't discriminate.
I can assure you of that.
The master hasn't called
you here to condemn you.
He wants to give you compensation.
What?
Compensation for killing Anastasia.
I understand.
Johan is lying to try to
get the truth from him.
As the son of a duke, the master was
bound to a fiancée through duty,
but it was her younger sister, Marie,
who stands here, that he fell in love with.
I'm sure you don't need
me to tell you the rest.
So the beautiful older sister was in the way.
Indeed. And so the master would
like to discreetly reward you.
In fact, he may even employ
you here at the castle.
And if you were a castle employee, then the
owner of the carriage rental couldn't yell at you.
Th-That would be too much, wouldn't it?
Please tell us the truth, Jacob.
That day, the old guy who runs
the shop was really excited.
Jacob, bring out the best carriage!
Huh? What's this about?
The lord's oldest daughter's getting married.
A job this big doesn't
come around very often.
Apologies for keeping you waiting, Baron.
We have prepared our very
best carriage for you.
It comes to roughly this amount.
Ridiculous!
I will only pay half that much.
B-But for that amount, we can't manage
to provide a decent carriage or inn.
Figuring out what to do about
that is your job, isn't it?
You may say so,
but the lady getting married is
your darling daughter, isn't it?
Jacob, you understand, don't you?
Lay a hand on the lord's daughter
and being fired is the least—
Yes, yes. I know.
But it's strange, isn't it?
Unlike that raggedy younger daughter,
the older one is supposed
to be adored, isn't she?
That's not for us to worry about!
Now, would you hurry up?!
Hey, my lady! You're just
as pretty as the rumors say!
I bet you've got your pick of the men, right?
Could it be you've actually
played around a bit?
Just joking. Sorry for being so crude.
I'm just a humble hired driver after all.
Not at all.
Her attitude made me realize,
the only way she could live was
by following her parents' orders.
She was a doll with nothing
more than her looks.
That's how I knew she wouldn't run away.
No matter what happened.
Wh-Why have you stopped the carriage?
The royal capital is close, isn't it?
We're camping here for the night.
And the horses are tired from the rain.
The river is dangerous, swollen with the rain!
Isn't that all the more reason to hurry?
I-If you dare lay a hand on the fiancée of
a count, do you know what will happen to you?
I don't, and I don't care.
When the count discovers that his
fiancée was defiled by a foreigner,
I wonder what'll happen to you.
Ow!
Mio!
He hasn't finished his story yet!
What're you doing?
What? I thought this was what you wanted!
Mio!
I'll take your place.
You! Where did you get the hair and clothes
for the doll that's at the baron's house?
Tell us!
I-I took the clothes off her myself.
And the hair?
Th-That was...
Don't move! Just stay still!
No!
She went and cut her own hair off!
Look! I've still got a scar from it!
You got what you deserved!
Wounded, you retrieved the clothes and hair,
then sold them to Lady Elvira, who was
in shock from her daughter's death.
I-I wasn't planning to sell
them to her from the beginning!
I heard that the baroness was looking
for materials to make a doll!
To cover up your own crime,
you destroyed the carriage,
and lied in your testimony, saying
that you were attacked by bandits.
That woman fell into the
river! That's the truth!
She was trying to run away and she slipped!
It was an accident!
I didn't kill her!
Please believe me!
That's enough.
I don't want to hear any more.
Marie.
My older sister died because
of you, didn't she?
B-But, you know? I think it was the right
move not to take that woman as your wife!
She had men's clothing that didn't
fit her hidden away in her bags!
What a crazy woman! She must've
had men besides her fiancé!
Even if she had married you,
she'd definitely have cheated on you!
Do not insult my sister!
Wh-What? Do you want to get
what that woman got, too?
Stop talking!
Sister, I...
I'm so sorry, Lord Kyros.
No, I'm the one who should apologize.
Until just now, I didn't
regret Anastasia's death.
What?
Neither did I.
Mio...
We thought that Anastasia had tyrannized
you the same way your parents did.
Sh-She didn't! Not even once!
Yes, I understand that now.
That's why I feel so guilty.
I thought that her death
was her divine punishment.
And that isn't all.
I thought that my mistakenly proposing
to her was a stroke of good luck.
Because of that error, you were safe, Marie.
That's what I believed.
Truthfully, it should have
been me in that carriage.
My sister was there in my place.
Marie... Will you allow me to
apologize at Anastasia's grave?
She doesn't have a grave.
My father said that a
gravestone would be a waste.
Her funeral was terribly plain, too.
In the end, my sister's name wasn't
even inscribed in the public cemetery.
I'd at least like to offer
her spirit some comfort.
Was there a place that Anastasia liked?
Flowers or food? What about a song?
I didn't know anything.
At some point, a huge gulf opened between us.
Me, who always wore tatters,
but could walk freely outside.
My sister, who was forced to dress
up in a tiny, enclosed garden.
A perfect being who should be beloved by all.
And I believed that was
why the gods took her away.
But even my sister... was just
a person living her life.
It's such an obvious thing,
but I'd forgotten that.
All of this is my fault.
I had no right to punch that man.
Neither do I.
Because I...
I'm just one of the many
people who killed Anastasia.
Rest well, Anastasia.
This waterway runs all the way to the
artisans' quarter in the royal capital.
While she was alive,
my sister once said that she wanted
to design clothes in the capital.
In such a lively place, perhaps
Anastasia won't feel lonely.
Yes.
Marie! Let's play!
I hope that's true.
It's been a week since then, and the
atmosphere in the castle has returned to normal.
Miss Marie is sewing.
And what are you doing?
If Marie pricks her finger on a needle,
I am here to treat it immediately.
Medicine
Box
So you're not doing anything.
It's finished!
Lord Kyros, I'm going to
use your hair for a moment.
Of course!
M-My son has turned into a faithful dog.
Please face the other way.
Like this?
Oh, now if you'll face forward.
Your hair is so beautiful.
Marie, your fingers move in such a
charming manner. It feels very nice.
You're both so innocent!
Like a couple who are
each others' first loves!
You're right. What of it?
So much happened that my giving
these to you has been delayed.
They're gifts for you from the market!
Oh, thank you so much!
How beautiful.
It's adorable, isn't it?
Lady Marie.
Yes, it is.
Souvenirs may be
the true pleasure of travel,
but I believe that spending money
and effort on me is a waste of—
Enough! Just accept her gift!
Poke Poke Poke Poke Poke Poke
You should just be happy
and shout with joy like me.
I-I'm sorry! I didn't mean to force it on you!
I accept.
Thank you, Lady Marie.
Thank you for everything
you do. I love you, Mio!
Since you arrived, Miss Marie,
everyone's attitudes have changed a little.
Have they?
And for you, Marie...
I have a gift as well.
The Tale of the Raggedy Red Cat!
It's been mended so beautifully!
Since you were going to
mend it yourself before...
This book is full of memories of
my sister. It's very dear to me.
Thank you so much.
I'm just glad you like it.
And there's this, too.
"Eminent Figures Around the World"?
I requested that one.
This is Baron Shaderan's mother, and
your grandmother, Marie. Sasha Tillich.
My grandmother when she was young.
Marie, you told me that Anastasia
looked just like her.
I thought this might help to capture
her likeness in a portrait.
Thank you, Lord Kyros.
So, your older sister took
after your grandmother.
Do you take after your mother?
In my height and facial features, yes,
but my mother is blonde.
I'm the only one with red hair.
Red hair will bring ruin upon
a house, so I was shunned.
What?! There are still people who believe
such an old-fashioned superstition?
Yes, agreed.
But why is my grandmother in
a record of eminent people?
My! You're related, but you haven't
heard of Sasha the Heroine?
She's quite famous.
What?
Despite being born during the war,
when women had no real status,
when she was merely eighteen,
she became a military interpreter,
commanding seven languages. A true genius.
Your grandmother revolutionized the
way that women advance in society.
She did?
The likes of your father may
have a bit of a complex.
She'd have been strict
about his education.
I'm not sure about that. My father didn't
interact with my grandmother very much.
There may have been some
discord between them.
About Baron Shaderan...
We sent an invitation
to the betrothal ceremony,
but received no reply.
What? That can't be!
The primary concern is that we have
no way of knowing if he'll attend.
The one who brought Marie here was
none other than the Baron.
Why would he oppose the marriage now?
I don't think my parents
ever meant for me to marry.
If I could offer one night's comfort, then we
wouldn't have to return my sister's betrothal gifts.
Still...
If he gains connections to
a ducal house through this marriage,
his own standing will rise significantly.
No matter how hard a worker you are, Marie...
Perhaps...
it's because Lady Marie was doing important
work that he can't entrust to an outsider.
But I was only doing simple things that
I learned from my grandmother as a child.
Your grandmother worked as the lord of the
land in the previous baron's stead, didn't she?
Y-Yes.
I heard that the formalities involved in
acting as the local lord were difficult.
And your grandmother and your father,
the current Baron Shaderan,
had discord between them.
Before, you told me that you wrote letters
on the lord's behalf, didn't you?
Can your father read and write in Flarian?
Yes, of course! I believe he can.
Have you ever actually
seen him use the language?
Now that you mention it, I haven't.
But it's impossible that he can't speak it.
Flarian is the communal
language of the nobility.
If he couldn't speak it, he wouldn't be
able to fulfill his duties as the lord.
I knew it.
It can't be. I don't believe it.
What is it?
Mio, send the House of
Shaderan a mandatory summons.
What?
If they won't respond to that either,
we'll have to take them
to trial in the kingdom's court.
I'm sorry, Marie. I wanted to settle
this as peacefully as possible.
What's going on?
What has my father done?
Four Days Later
Marie.
Hey, everyone! It's the prince everyone
loves, Luiphon Sandhalkia Diltz!
Why is it you?
Darling Mio, you love to roughhouse.
Enough of that. Eat before it gets cold.
This is delicious!
I should expect no less of
the chef of Granado Castle.
I'd love to have him at the royal—
You're too kind, Your Highness.
He's slimmed down quite a bit, hasn't he?
The betrothal ceremony will
be attended by royalty,
nobles, and commoners from
many countries, so...
Oh, I see. You've been incredibly busy
developing recipes and sourcing ingredients.
Toppo, don't push yourself too hard.
Not at all.
All of this is what I, Toppo, wish to
create, so I'm more fired up than ever!
Toppo.
Kyros, you really have the
best luck with your servants.
Yes. But more importantly,
what brings you here today?
Actually...
Your engagement ring.
I came to check the sizing before
the stone is secured in place.
Now, dear Marie, hold out your hand.
Stop right there!
What?
I'm just checking the size.
No! Not even just to check the
size! Go away for a minute!
Yes, yes.
May I check the size?
Yes.
The stone isn't set in place yet, so
please don't move your hand too much.
It's perfect.
I didn't know that a ring
could feel this nice to wear.
You haven't worn a ring before?
I haven't.
I'm so glad I stopped Luiphon!
Lord Kyros looked for a stone
to match the color of my hair.
This ring really was made just for me.
Marie...
Thank you.
The fact that my first ring is a
gift from you makes me truly happy.
I love you, Marie.
I love you from the bottom of my heart.
I feel the same!
More than anyone else in the world...
it's you that I...
Hey! Are you done yet?
So, what do you think of it?
Th-The workmanship is wonderful.
I thought that the only artisan capable
of this kind of work was Norman.
Are you referring to the
button artisan Smith Norman?
Yes.
I know he's elderly, but it's
a shame that he retired.
He really had amazing skills.
He was a button maker who also made rings?
Buttons were originally a
type of valuable jewelry.
Being particular about them shows
care in one's appearance.
Sometimes clothes are even made
to match a set of buttons.
Oh, I see.
Indeed. The only one capable of executing
the design of that ring may be that Norman.
What?
You don't mean... Smith
Norman himself made this?!
That's right! It's my real gift to you.
I went to him in his retirement
and begged, I'll have you know!
Me, of all people.
No wonder!
Thank you, Prince Luiphon.
But Norman is famous for being stubborn.
I'm amazed that you convinced him.
He seemed to have taken on a new apprentice,
so perhaps he's had a change of heart.
Apprentice?
Yes. Apparently, he's taken in
a foundling or street urchin.
It happened three months ago in the
royal capital's artisans' quarter.
What?
A foundling?
If they were from outside the capital,
was it a farmer's child?
Regional disparities are a problem for the
royal government, aren't they, Prince Luiphon?
Three months ago...
The royal capital's artisans' quarter...
That's... It can't be!
Our lady is beautiful,
but when it comes to her older
sister, her face always clouds over.
Next time, "Please Call Off the Betrothal."
Episode 10 "Please Call
Off the Betrothal"
I'd simply hate it if you didn't watch.